Okay at this moment, to say our game is easy is probably beyond and an understatement.
You kind of just sit there and wait for the ball.
But that stops here.
It's time to make this game a whole lot more challenging and fun by embracing randomness.
So looking at our code for our point direction, you can see that it just kind of points up.
So this behavior is expected as that is what we're telling the ball to do.
But what we really want is for the board to not just point straight up each time, but we wanted to
point just a bit to one side.
So how could we do this?
Well, remember how I said this code is kind of like Lego with different pieces can fit in and on one
another.
Well, if you look, you'll notice this area has this circle or this oval type shape.
Now looking through our code, you will see that a lot of code is a shape.
For example, if we take this exposition block, see how we can put it inside this point direction block
because it's the same shape.
However, you will notice that if we play the game now, the ball does not do what we want.
So this is clearly not the block we're looking for.
But to give you a hint, the block that we need is actually found under the operators group.
Now remember what we said at the start.
Operators are code blocks that deal with mathematics, which are now important for us to use, so why
not give it a try?
Try to see if you can find the code block that we will use to get our ball bouncing correctly.
Just pause and give it a go.
Did you find it?
Well, let's have a look.
We basically want the ball to bounce upwards and also a bit to the right or the left.
So if you look at this code, you will see that there is this pick random block.
So here we can simply put this block in the point direction.
So quickly playing you can see it kind of does what we want but not exactly.
It's more just drifting to the side.
And that's because we need to change these numbers.
So removing this again, we can click our point direction to get an idea of what numbers should be moving
this arrow.
I would say that -45 and 45 are a pretty good direction.
So let's input that into our pick.
Random.
And again put it back into our code.
So clicking play again.
There you have it.
That is much better.
Our game is finally getting somewhere and it's a lot more challenging.
And yes, who said math isn't fun?